A Guide to the Carey Wilbur Butterworth Papers, 1890-1947
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Carey Wilbur Butterworth Papers, 1890-1947
The Library of Virginia
51472
.675 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
Carey Wilbur Butterworth was born in Petersburg, Virginia on 22 October 1868. He was the son of Joseph Wilbur Butterworth and Martha Thomas Southall. He married 1) Ida Burns Little (1870-1905) on 23 June 1892, and 2) Mamie Young Little (1879-1973) on 19 June 1907. Butterworth was employed by the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad for over fifty years. He died in Richmond on 5 December 1949 and is buried in Riverview Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1890-1947, of Carey Wilbur Butterworth (1868-1949) relating to his work as an agent for the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad at Doswell station in Hanover County, and later at Milford station in Caroline County, Virginia. The collection includes correspondence, much of it with William D. Duke (1873-1951), company general manager, and concerns employee hiring, wages, job performance, and working conditions at the two stations. There are also accounts and receipts, applications for weekly settlements, cartoons and drawings, certificates, check rolls, employee pay receipts, freight bills and bills of lading, monthly accounts current, Order of Railroad Telegraphers materials, remittances, and retirement benefit information.
Contents List
- Accounts and Receipts. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Annual Reports, 1932, 1947. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Applications for Weekly Settlements. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cartoons/Drawings. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Certificates. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Check Rolls. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1890. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1895-1898. (Box 1, Folder 8-11)
- Correspondence, 1904-1905. (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
- Correspondence, 1907. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1909-1920. (Box 1, Folder 15-26)
- Correspondence, 1923. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, 1927-1928. (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
- Correspondence, 1930. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, 1932. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, 1934. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, 1936. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Correspondence, 1938-1939. (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
- Correspondence, 1941. (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Correspondence, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Correspondence, undated. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- The Country Merchant (New Concord, OH), August 1901. (Box PP Oversize Box, Folder n/a)
- Deed. (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Diary of Agnes Gray Butterworth, 1919. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Drawing/Sketch (Oversize). (Box PP Oversize Box, Folder n/a)
- Employee Job Performance. (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Employee Pay Receipts/Stubs. (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Forms/Stationary (Blank). (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Freight Bills/Bills of Lading. (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Freight Bill Overcharges. (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Greeting Cards. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Minutes. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Monthly Accounts Current. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "National Housing Act" - Federal Housing Administration Booklet. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Order of Railroad Telegraphers. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Parnassus Club. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Patent. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Plan of New Water Station at Milford, 1916. (Box PP Oversize Box, Folder n/a)
- Remittances, 1911. (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
- Retirement Benefits. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Rules and Regulations/Schedule of Wages, 1910. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Virginian Railway Company - Authorities for Expenditure, 1922-1924. (Box 2, Folder 13)